This is a. 44 Magnum, the most powerful handgun in the world.
這是四四型的連發手槍，全世界威力最大的手槍
And it could blow your head clean off.
可以把你的腦袋轟掉
Do you feel lucky?
你覺得自己很幸運嗎？
Mr. Ricca! How do you feel about your acquittal?
雷卡先生，你對自己被判定無罪釋放有何感想？
It proves what I always said, I had nothing to do with Scarza's murder.
這證明我說的話都是真的，我跟史卡茲謀殺案一點關係都沒有。
Who could have killed Anthony Scarza and his family?
你知道是誰殺了史卡茲及他的家人嗎？
That's a stupid question. Get off my back!
那是個蠢問題，別來煩我。
Mr. Weinstein, explain the technicality involving the lack of admissible evidence.
溫斯頓先生，請解釋缺乏佐證的法律意義。
That's a legality that can't be explained at this time.
那是個現在說不清的法律用詞
Mr. Weinstein, you don't seem surprised about the decision.
溫斯頓先生，你似乎對判決結果不感意外
I don't know why they waste the taxpayers' money.
我不知道，他們幹嗎浪費納稅人的錢
This whole thing is an arbitrary attack on a legitimate businessman.
這整件事都是對守法生意人的獨斷攻擊
- Do you have any comments? - What, dear?
雷卡先生，你有其他的看法嗎？ 什麼？
Do you have any other comments?
你有其他的看法嗎？雷卡先生
I'll give you a comment: Their minds are dead.
對，我可以告訴你，他們的腦袋掛了
- What do you mean by that? - Their minds are dead.
你是什麼意思？ 我是說他們的腦袋掛了
Mr. Ricca means he is very pleased with the decision.
我想雷卡先生的意思是他對判決結果很滿意
There's a big crowd. Do you fear for your life?
外面聚集大批民眾，你會擔心自己的安危嗎？
No, of course not.
不，當然不會
Mr. Estabrook.
伊斯塔布洛克先生
As the prosecutor, how do you feel about the court's decision?
身為檢察官，你對法庭判決有何看法？
It's happened before, it'll probably happen again.
這種事以前曾經發生過，也可能會再發生
I have no more comments.
其餘的無可奉告
I'm sorry, no comments. No comments!
對不起，無可奉告
I have no comments.
我無可奉告
You know what I think? I'll tell you what I think!
你知道我在想什麼嗎？ 我告訴你
Fuck the courts, that's what I think!
去他的想法，那就是我的想法
They've already wasted too much time worrying about the rights of killers!
他們浪費太多時間去思考街頭殺手的人權
Ricca, you're a killer!
雷卡，你是兇手
Get in the car! Go on!
快上車
Murderer!
兇手
Today the noted labor leader Carmine Ricca...
今天，著名的工會領袖卡邁雷卡
...was acquitted on a technicality: the lack of admissible evidence.
因缺乏可採用的證據，被判無罪釋放
Ricca had been charged with complicity...
雷卡被控共謀殺害了
...in the murders of labor reformer Anthony Scarza and his family.
工會改革者史卡茲及他的家人
When he appeared outside the courthouse this afternoon, a free man...
當他今天下午被判無罪釋放出現在法庭外時
...it touched off a wild, mob-like demonstration.
民眾發動了猶如暴動般的示威遊行
But the police were finally able to bring it under control...
但警方最後控制住情況
...and there have been no reports of injuries.
無人受傷
But one can expect an uproar from an angry and alarmed crowd...
但憤怒的民眾全心祈求
...which fully expected Ricca to be convicted.
雷卡能夠被判有罪
And I'm sure we haven't heard the last of the Ricca case.
我相信雷卡案會有繼續發展
Art Brown reporting from city hall.
這是亞特布朗在法院所作的現場報導
Cop.
是條子
Gino, for chrissake.
查諾，我的天啊
Come on, Carmine. I'm driving this thing like a baby carriage.
得了，卡邁，我剛剛的速度只有嬰兒車那麼快
Could I see your driver's license, please?
麻煩把駕照給我看看
Do you know who that is sitting back there?
你知道是誰坐在後面嗎？
I'll still have to see your driver's license, please.
我還是要看你的駕照
I'll have to find it.
我得找找看
Do you know why you're being stopped?
你知道你為什麼被攔下來嗎？
Yes, we know, officer, and you're making a big mistake.
是的，我們知道，警官，你犯了一個大錯
- You crossed a double line back there. - A double line?
你剛剛越過雙黃線
Take it easy.
越過雙黃線？
Whatever you say, officer.
別激動，你說的都對，警官
I just happened to find it, sir.
我剛好找到了，警官
That's right, Simple Simon.
沒錯，辛普賽門
Check, see if it's stolen.
看看那是不是偷來的
I want this bastard busted out of his job.
我要那個混蛋被革職
We'll take care of this guy. You fellas, just take it easy.
我們會處理他的 你們別激動好嗎？
- This car registered to you? - To him.
這部車是你的？ 是他的
- I'll have to see the registration. - Come on, give me that license.
我要看行駛執照 好的，先把駕駛執照還給我
Hi, Harry. Is this your case?
嗨，哈堙A這是你的案子嗎？
Walter?
華特？
Hello, Harry. What are you doing here?
你好，哈堙A你來這媟F嘛？
This couldn't have happened to a nicer bunch.
這就是做壞人的下場
Ricca, Weinstein, his attorney. James Cantina, the driver.
雷卡，溫斯頓跟他的律師，詹姆士康提那，還有司機
What about the bodyguard?
保鏢呢？
We're checking that out now, lieutenant.
我們還在查，副局長
Looks like somebody saved the taxpayers a lot of money, doesn't it?
看起來有人幫納稅人省了不少錢，對吧？
Callahan, what are you doing here? You're on loan to stakeout.
卡拉漢，你來這媟F什麼？ 你應該去監視嫌疑犯的
We had nothing hot on, besides, we were close.
我們毫無發現 而且人就在附近
Callahan, you get your lying ass in gear and get back to that stakeout squad.
卡拉漢，你立刻給我上車 去支援監視小組
Anything else, you call it in.
有什麼事就用電話聯絡
- Who do you think did this, Briggs? - You're on loan to stakeout, Callahan.
你覺得這是誰幹的？布立基？ 你正在監視嫌疑犯，卡拉漢
That's right, lieutenant, you saw to that.
沒錯，副局長，那是你下的命令
I've got nothing personal against you, Callahan.
我對你沒有私人偏見，卡拉漢
But we can't have the public crying, "police brutality"...
但是我們無法承受每次你一上街
...every time you're on the street.
就有民眾大喊“員警打人”
You just might need me on a job like this.
你可以需要我來偵辦這類的案子
Whoever did this was very good at it.
不管兇手是誰，他都是個高手
You'd sure be the one to know, Harry.
你心堳亄M楚，哈
- Well, I just work for this city, Briggs. - So do I.
好了，我只是在為民眾工作，布立基 我也是
Longer than you.
而且資歷比你深
And I never had to take my gun out of its holster once. I'm proud of that.
我從來沒拔出過槍，一次也沒有。我以此為榮
Well, you're a good man, lieutenant.
你是個好人，副局長
A good man always knows his limitations.
一個好人知道自己的能力所在
Lt. Briggs?
布立基副局長？
What did you get?
有什麼線索？
Well, it looks like they were killed with a Magnum.
看起來他們被連環手槍所殺
The boys now are checking the blood types and for fingerprints.
他們現在在查血型和指紋
What do you have?
那是什麼？
Driver's license. Doesn't look at all like the usual gangster crap, does it?
司機的駕照，看起來不像一般的黑道火拼，對吧？
Briggs has his nose up his ass today.
布立基今天心情不太好
I guess he thinks that's where his promotion is.
我想他一定在擔心他的升遷問題
See you later, Harry.
呵呵，待會兒見，哈
What's with you and Briggs anyway?
你和布立基之間到底怎麼了？
Jealousy.
嫉妒
He knows this is the kind of case I should be on. It's just a matter of time.
他知道這個案子應該由我來偵辦 那只是時間問題
Hey, Early, wanna get in on this?
厄利，你想插手嗎？
What the hell is that about?
那是怎麼一回事？
They're giving odds on how long you'll stay alive being my partner.
他們或許在賭你做我的搭檔 可以活多久
- Are you kidding? - Nope.
你在開玩笑嗎？
How long did your last partner go?
你上一個搭檔和你呆了多久？
A couple of weeks.
幾個星期
Don't worry, he's still alive, teaching college.
別擔心，他還活著 在大學堭衩
You have another trade, Smith?
你還有事嗎？史密斯
- No, no. Do you? - No, but Bill Mackenzie does.
沒有，沒有，你呢？
Who in the hell is Bill Mackenzie?
誰是比爾邁克肯基？
He's an ex-Homicide man, has a snack shop out at the airport.
他是兇殺組的退休警官 現在在機場開了家漢堡店
Greatest burgers in town. Hungry?
他做的漢堡是全市最好吃的 你餓了嗎？
- How can you be hungry after seeing that? - Seeing what?
你看過那個後還吃得下？ 看過什麼？
So Ricca finally bought it. There must be hope for the world yet.
雷卡終於買車了 這世界還是有希望的
How about you? Do you want something?
你要吃什麼？
- We got chili and garlic bread today. - No, thank you. I don't feel very hungry.
我們今天有辣味大蒜麵包 不，謝了，我不餓
In broad daylight at close range? Must've looked like ripe melons.
白天在近距離下看得清清楚楚 一定很像爛香瓜
Operations Supervisor, Mr. Phoenix, use white courtesy telephone.
呼叫安全小組組長 請用白色公務電話聯絡
Now all keep calm.
好了，現在保持冷靜 我們第一件要做的事是你....
I'll never forget the Floyd case.
我忘不了佛洛德的案子
Got it with an axe during the rush hour.
他在巔峰時間拿斧頭劈人
How about some cream pie?
要來點奶油派嗎？
- Operations Supervisor, Mr. Phoenix... - I don't think so.
呼叫安全小組組長，費尼克斯先生 請用白色公務電話聯絡
We've got 90 people being terrorized by those maniacs...
這些暴徒挾持了九十名人質
...in boarding area B right now.
飛機現在停靠在B區
What's taking so long? They said they'd be there in 15 minutes.
他們怎麼那麼久還沒到？ 他們說過十五分鐘就會到嗎？
Where's that overseas pilot?
國際航班的飛行員在哪里？
I don't understand. How did they get through security?
我不明白，菲爾 他們是怎麼通過安檢的？
- I don't know. - Any problem here?
我不知道 出了什麼事情嗎？
What are you doing here?
你在這媟F什麼
- I'm sorry, you'll have to leave. - I'm a police officer.
對不起，請你離開 我是員警
We've got two frantic hijackers on our New York flight.
有兩個瘋狂劫機犯 劫持了我們飛往紐約的班機
- Have you called the FBI? - They're on their way here right now.
你們聯絡聯邦調查局了嗎？ 聯絡了，他們正在趕過來
But the hijackers want an overseas pilot before they take off.
但是劫匪要一名國際航班的飛行員 在他們起飛前登機
May I make a suggestion?
想聽聽我的建議嗎？
Good afternoon.
下午好
You took your goddamn time about it. Now, close that door!
你還真會拖延時間 把門關上
All right, what's in there?
好了，那婺佽菑偵礡H
Overseas charts and flight plans.
國際航班表和飛行計畫
Set it down!
把它放下
All right, turn around.
好了，轉過身去
Stay there.
站著別動
All right, turn around here.
好了，進去
Here! Now get in there.
拿去，現在快給我進去
- It's all yours now. - All right, get this thing up!
一切都交給你了 好了，飛機準備起飛
Where to?
去哪里？
You get us up, I'll tell you where to when we're up.
先讓飛機起飛 我會告訴你我們去哪里
You wanna put us in take-off position?
你要我們就起飛位置，對吧？
Starting three.
啟動三號引擎
Move it!
快點！
All right, I'll take it.
好了，我聽到了
That's right, lieutenant. We were lucky to have one of your men here.
沒錯，副局長， 還好你的人在這
He's onboard now, an Inspector Callahan.
卡拉漢警官 他現在上了飛機
Callahan!
卡拉漢？
Excuse me, captain. I know this may sound silly...
不好意思，機長 我知道這聽起來很蠢
...but can you fly?
...但是，你會開飛機嗎？
No. Never had a lesson.
不，從來都沒有學過
Sit down!
坐下！
What are you doing here, lieutenant?
你在這媟F什麼？副局長
Harry. You crazy son of a bitch. I could've killed you.
哈堙I你這個瘋子 我差點撞死你
Yeah, I noticed that, Charlie. What the hell you doing?
我注意到了，查理 你好嗎？
I haven't seen you in a coon's age.
好久不見了
I been meaning to drop by, but we've been kind of busy.
我本來想去看看你 但我們一直都很忙
Yeah, well, I ain't living with Carol anymore.
對，我沒跟卡蘿住在一起了
Sorry to hear that.
抱歉會這樣
Yeah. It's my third time at bat.
是啊，這是我連續三次被踢出局了
Where's the time go?
舊日好時光到哪里去了呢？
I'm afraid of time.
我開始害怕時間流逝了
I know you 10 years already, ever since I first came out here, you realize that?
從我到這堥茪妨 我認識你也十年了，你知道嗎？
You don't look older to me. Do I look older to you?
我覺得你看起來一點都沒老 你覺得我老了嗎？
Why don't you put in for some desk work, Charlie?
你為什麼不調回內勤呢？查理
You don't need the streets anymore.
你不需要在街上巡邏了
We should've put our 20 in the Marines.
我們該把這些美好的年華獻給海軍的
These days, a cop kills a hoodlum on the street...
現在要是員警在街上把流氓打死了
...he might as well just dump the body someplace.
他最好是把屍體藏起來
Because those snot-nosed young bastards...
因為那些弱智檢察官會想盡一切辦法折磨他
...down at the DA's office will crucify them one way or another.
然後坐在辦公室就可以把人殺死
A hood can kill a cop, but let a cop kill a hood...
流氓可以殺員警 但要是員警把流氓給殺了.....
Am I right?
我說的對吧？
You put in plenty of time, why don't you go for retirement?
你工作太久了 你為什麼不申請退休呢？
What the hell, you don't need this.
怎麼了？ 你不需要當員警的
I know you 10 years. I'll tell you something, I'll never retire.
我認識你十年了，我來告訴你一件事情 這是我們的秘密
Never.
我永遠都不會退休
I'm going out fighting.
我要繼續鬥爭
That's the only way to go. Am I right?
那時唯一的辦法，對吧？
You boys rookies?
你們是員警？
Yes, sir. Traffic.
是的，我們是交通警察
I'm John Davis. This is Phil Sweet.
我是約翰大衛斯 他是菲爾史威特
That's Red Astrachan, Mike Grimes.
那邊是瑞德亞斯特拉跟麥克格林姆
- You're Inspector Harry Callahan, no? - That's right.
你是哈堨d拉漢警官，對吧？ 是的
What are you doing here? Don't you have regular times for this?
你們這時來這媟F什麼？ 你們沒有固定的上班時間嗎？
You shouldn't be on the streets if you can't shoot well.
現在如果槍法不准 就別上街去執勤
- Killers don't make allowances. - You're in big trouble.
殺手可是不會對你手下留情的 你會惹上一身的麻煩的
Can't fault you there.
你們說的對
Are you shooting in the combat championship next week?
下周你會參加射擊比賽嗎？
I always do.
我一向都會參加的
- You win every year, don't you? - Became sort of an institution around here.
你每年都會贏得比賽，對嗎？ 那已經變成這堛熄Е峇F
Yes, sir, we've heard all about you.
是的，我們聽說過你的事蹟
This is about the only time I get this place alone.
這是我唯一能在這媬W處的時候
We'll leave if you'd like the range to yourself.
如果你想獨自呆著的話 我們可以離開
No, that's all right.
不，沒關係
What kind of a load do you use in that. 44?
你的四四型連發手槍裝的是什麼子彈？
A light special.
我用的是特別的輕質子彈
This size gun gives me better control and less recoil...
我覺得這種槍跟加了槍塞的
...than a. 357 Magnum with wadcutters.
三五七型連發手槍相比，控制力道比較好 後坐力也比較輕
That's not bad.
還不錯
Care to try?
想試試看嗎？
No, sir. No, I don't think so.
不，長官，我想還是算了吧
- Come on, give it a try. - Go on, Sweet.
試試看吧，史威特
I'm farsighted.
我有點近視
Don't drop it.
別掉地上了
Hey, that's not bad.
不錯嘛
Well, I think it's just a little heavy for me. I missed one.
我覺得槍有點重，我一發沒打中
You'll get used to it.
是啊，你會習慣的
Where did you learn to shoot? Not around here.
告訴我，你在哪里學射擊的？ 一定不是在這
No, sir, no. Airborne Rangers, Special Forces.
不，長官，不是 是在亞爾班特種突擊隊
And the rest of these guys, even close?
其他人更厲害嗎？
Well, Grimes here, he's...
我想格林姆跟我差不多
- Astrachan's a little better on a good day. - A little bit.
亞斯特拉在手氣好的時候比我們好 手氣好？
And Davis is just dog nuts. He's a lot better.
大衛斯是個瘋子 他比我們厲害多了
A lot better? Sure show a sense of style. Sweet, is it?
比你們厲害多了？他耍起槍來一定很帥 史威特，對不對？
Yes, sir.
是的，長官
When I get back on Homicide, I hope you boys will come see me.
我回兇殺組後 希望你們能來找我
- Good. - Thank you very much, we'd like that.
太棒了，非常感謝你 謝謝，我們非常願意
Let's go!
走吧
- Good night, sir. - Good night.
晚安，長官 晚安
Who buys? The sun was in my eyes.
誰請客？ 太陽照到我的眼睛
- You got to be on, Grimes. - The sun is always in your eyes.
少來了，格林姆 你老是被太陽照到眼睛
How come I always have to buy the beer for you turkeys?
我老是要請你們這些混蛋喝啤酒
Where do you want to go?
你們要去哪里？ 走吧，把帽子戴上，快點！
Put your hat on!
戴上你的帽子
Come on now, baby.
現在過來，寶貝
Will you look at my ring?!
你們看看我的戒指 看到我的戒指你們就知道了
It's beautiful!
好漂亮哦
Is this a gang war?
是幫派火拼嗎？
You have nothing to say?
沒有別的消息了嗎？
- Do you expect more murder or violence? - I have nothing to say at this time.
會發生更嚴重的黑社會火拼嗎？ 我現在無可奉告
- Is this a gang war, lieutenant? - No comment.
是黑道火拼嗎？副局長 不予置評
There were 200 murders last year. Do you want to make a comment on that?
去年本市發生了兩百起兇殺案 你要對此發表評論嗎？
There'll be no bombs in pools. This town belongs to the people.
游泳池堣ㄦ|有炸彈 這個城市屬於所有的市民
We're gonna have law and order here.
我們要執行法律，維護秩序
That's all I have to say at this time.
這是我目前可以說的
What does that mean, lieutenant?
副局長，那是什麼意思？
- You're it.
你扮鬼
Don't you want to play with us?
你不跟我們玩嗎？
- Well, I don't know, sweetheart. - Just a little while?
我不知道，親愛的 只要一下子就好
You're really getting the full treatment.
你真是吃了頓大餐
It's not often you get a sit-down dinner.
你不經常好好的吃頓飯，對嗎？
Okay, kids. All right, that's enough.
好了，孩子們，夠了
- Just a little bit more, just five minutes? - Let's go, let's go.
再玩一下子，再玩五分鐘好嗎？ 走了走了
Say good night to Harry and off to bed.
跟哈婸§艀w，然後都去睡覺
- Good night. - Good night, my love.
晚安 晚安，親愛的
- Take it easy.
忍耐點，好嗎？
- Bye. - Good night, Harry.
再見 晚安，哈
Take the jacket out of your mouth, sweetheart.
別用嘴巴咬衣服 親愛的
Boy, sometimes they're too much for me.
老天，有時候我真的搞不懂他們
But then I can't afford a woman coming in anymore.
但是我請不起保姆來幫我照顧他們
I think you manage quite well.
我覺得你做得很好
Well, I just laugh all day long.
我只能一笑置之
I'm glad you called.
很高興你能來看我們
Tell me, have you seen Charlie?
告訴我，你見過查理嗎？
Yes, I saw him last night.
我昨晚見過他
Wanted to see the kids...
他想看孩子
...and then he started playing a little Russian roulette with his revolver.
結果他開始拿著他的左輪手槍 玩起俄羅斯轉盤
What happened?
發生什麼事了？
What could I do? I went next door, we finally got him to stop.
我能怎麼辦呢？ 我們到最後讓他平靜下來
What do you tell your children...
當孩子問你
...when they ask why their father tried to shoot himself?
為什麼爸爸要開槍射自己時 你該怎麼回答？
What did you tell them?
你怎麼告訴他們的？
I just said it was a special kind of sickness that some people have...
我說有些人會得很特別的病
...and that there are doctors who could cure it. As if they could.
有醫生能幫他們把病治好 就想他們真的可以一樣
Do you know where he's living right now?
你知道他現在住在哪里嗎？
I don't know and I don't care anymore.
我不知道，我也不在乎
He's so sick. He shouldn't be allowed to carry a gun.
他太變態了 他不該被許可帶槍的
Do you know that he was living in North Beach with some nude dancer?
你知道他曾經跟脫衣舞娘住在北灣嗎？
Oh, well, I'm glad I'm over that one.
哦，我很高興結束那段婚姻
I do have to survive.
我必須活下去才行
You will.
你會的
You know, Harry, if I ask you a personal question, would you mind?
你知道的，哈 你介意我問你一個問題嗎？
Sure, go ahead.
當然不介意，問吧
Are you sure? Because, well, it's a little difficult.
你確定嗎？ 因為這問題有點不好回答
Look, we've been friends a long time, go ahead and ask.
聽著，我們是老朋友了，你直說吧
Well, I'm just wondering why you've never made a pass at me.
我一直在想，為什麼你從來都不追求我
Why?
為什麼？
Goddamn it.
該死！
With all those kids do you think I'll ever get laid?
有這些孩子，你覺得我輕鬆得起來嗎？
Hello?
你好？
Yes, just a moment.
是的，請等一下
It's for you.
是找你的
What's happening?
發生什麼事了？
Yeah?
喂？
Yeah, Early, I saw it on TV.
喂？是的，厄利，我看到電視報導了
I'll be right down. I'll come in the back way.
我馬上回去 我馬上到
- That's it, right? - I have to go.
就這樣了，對吧？ 我得走了
Good night, Harry.
晚安，哈
Good night, sweetheart.
晚安，親愛的
How's it going?
情況如何？
By the magazine rack.
嫌犯在雜誌架旁邊
The owner remembers seeing him just before the last robbery.
店主說，在上次搶案發生前看到過他
Yeah, he doesn't look much like a paying customer, does he?
對，他看起來不像會付錢買東西的客人對吧？
- There's a car parked out in front. - That's right, a no-parking zone.
前面停了一部車 對，停在禁停區
Get over there by the door with that shotgun.
到門邊去拿散彈槍
Okay.
好
You think it'll be a hit or a miss?
你覺得我們會抓錯人嗎？
Well, here's three salty-looking dudes.
這三個傢伙看起來不像好人
Freeze, nigger!
別動，黑鬼！
- What you got there? - Don't you go setting off no alarm.
不要試圖去碰警鈴
You. Get over here, fast.
你，過來這邊！快
- You got a safe, nigger? - No.
你們有保險箱嗎？ 沒有
You lying sack of shit.
你這個騙子
Just take it easy. Take it easy now.
好了，別激動，慢慢來
Suck it.
見鬼了
I'll kill you. I said, suck it.
我要殺了你，我說見鬼了
You go find that safe.
你得去找保險箱
Right here is where I kill me a nigger.
我要在這堭了這個黑鬼
Get on your knees.
跪下
- Better get out there now. - Not yet.
我們最好快出去
Get on your knees.
跪下
Police!
員警
Drop it!
把槍放下！
All right, hold it!
好了，不許動！
I never shot a man.
我從來沒有開槍打過人
Why don't you help the lady?
你為何不去幫那個女士呢？
It's all right, ma'am.
好了，女士，來吧
You handled yourself real well tonight.
你今晚的表現很好
You work close. Man, you work close.
你害我快嚇死了
Hey, where are you guys off to?
嗨，你們要去哪里？
- The Downtown Bowl on Eddy Street. - Oh, yeah. See you later.
艾迪街的市區保齡球館 哦，好，呆會兒見
- You know them? - They came from the academy after me.
你認識那些傢伙？ 是的，他們是我警校的學弟
They stick together like fly paper.
他們就跟粘蠅紙一樣粘在一起
Everybody thought they were queer for each other.
大家都覺得他們在搞同性戀
I'll tell you something, if the rest of you could shoot like them...
我告訴你，如果局堥銗L人開槍能像他們一樣准
...I wouldn't care if the whole damn department was queer.
我不在乎局堛漱H是不是全都是同性戀
Excuse me, it's very important.
對不起，我有急事
What do you think you're doing?
天啊，約翰 你在幹什麼？
1000 O'Farrell.
歐法瑞街1000號
We're not going to get there unless you keep your eyes on the road.
除非你眼睛看著路 否則我們永遠也到不了
Right on. 1000 O'Farrell.
是的，歐法瑞街1000號
Too bad you're not on welfare.
真可惜你得不到好處
I'd give you a freebie.
我願意請你免費上一次
Drive.
開車
- Sidney, I was just on my way to see you. - Where to?
辛蒂，我正要去找你 去哪里？
- Just keep on going until I tell you to stop. - Yes, sir.
照直往前開，叫你停再停 是，先生
Drop that flag.
把隔離板拉下來
- You're on your way to see me? - Yes, Sidney, honest.
你正要來找我嗎？ 是的，辛蒂，我....
How come you didn't come by the crib?
你為什麼沒到酒吧來？
- Well- - Don't shit me.
這個... 別騙我
I wouldn't do that.
我不會走的
- I've been waiting for you for one week. - I've been working the convention.
我等了你一個星期 我一直在飯店堭筍
- No telephones in that hotel? - I've been working like hell, you know?
飯店媄纗D沒有電話嗎？ 你不知道我一直在工作嗎？
Let me show you.
我拿給你看
- See? It's all here, all I got. - All?
看，我賺的錢全都在這堙A全在這堙I 全部的？
Looks like you've been holding out on me.
是 看來你在背後偷偷搞鬼了
No, I haven't. I've been straight with you, Sidney. You know me.
不，我沒有，我一直都對你很誠實 辛蒂，你很瞭解我
Damn right I know you. Let's see how much there is in the titty bank.
對，我很瞭解你 我來看看你這娷瓣F多少
Hello, Mr. Green.
哈，鈔票先生
Check out the snatch bank too.
現在再來看看這塈a
Damn right I know you.
我真是太瞭解你了
I was gonna give it all to you, but you didn't give me a chance.
我本來就要全部拿給你的 辛蒂，但你沒有給我機會
Bitch, you had your chance. I was your last chance.
機會，你這個婊子 我給了你機會
Everybody else in town threw your black ass out.
城堛漱H都想把你趕出去
Help me!
救命啊！
Good day, sir. Is this car registered to you?
你好，先生 這是你的車嗎？
Yes, sir. This is my car.
是的，這是我的車
You must be new. You know who I am?
你一定是新來的，你知道我是誰嗎？
I'll still have to see your license and registration, sir.
我還是要看看你的駕照和行駛證，先生
I believe you were speeding coming across the bridge.
你在過橋時超速了
Hi.
嗨
What's your name?
你叫什麼名字？
Sunny.
桑妮
I've been living here for six months now. It's funny I've never met you before.
我搬到這堣賒茪諵F 奇怪的是我從來沒有看見過你
Well, I work a lot.
我經常加班
I know.
我知道
- You're the cop who lives upstairs. - That's right.
你是住在樓上的員警 沒錯
Mind if I ask you a question?
我可以問你一個問題嗎？
No, go ahead.
可以啊，問吧
What does a girl have to do to go to bed with you?
女孩子要怎樣做才能跟你上床？
Try knocking on the door.
試試敲敲我的門好了
- Hi.
-嗨
Do you always live in the dark?
你總是不開燈嗎？
Well, you meet a better class of people in the dark sometimes. Come on in.
有時候在黑暗的地方才能遇見好人 請進
Sit down.
請坐
No, actually, I'm entertaining a young lady friend.
不，事實上 我跟一個女孩子在一起
Put your pants back on, Callahan, and come to the city morgue right away.
把你的褲子穿上，卡拉漢 立刻到市局調查處來
The morgue? What the hell for, Briggs?
調查處？為什麼？布立基？
I'm not on Homicide anymore. I'm a stakeout man now, remember?
我不是兇殺組的成員 我現在是監視組的人，記得嗎？
Not anymore, Callahan.
不再是了，卡拉漢
You and your partner are back on Homicide.
你跟你的搭檔一起被調回兇殺組了
This is a little dramatic, isn't it, Briggs? Not your usual style.
這太戲劇化了吧，布立基？ 不像是你平常的做派
It's meant to be, Callahan.
這是真的，卡拉漢
This thing might be bigger than even we think it is.
聽著，這個案子比我們想像中的要大
Hijacking and gambling.
劫車和賭博
Trucking.
卡車搶劫案
Narcotics and prostitution.
吸毒及賣淫
This is the cream in the bottle.
顯而易見，卡拉漢
Someone wants to put the courts out of business.
有人在替法院執法
So far, you've said nothing wrong.
到目前為止，你說的都很正確
This one just came in an hour ago.
這具屍體是一個小時前送來的
Somebody wants it all. This guy was just a pimp.
兇手只想殺他 死者是個皮條客
That's one of his girls.
那是他的妓女
How did she get it?
她是怎麼被殺的？
Sometime before he got hit, he poured a can of drain cleaner down her throat.
在他遭到襲擊之前 他強行給她灌下洗廁劑
That shows a certain sense of style.
這真的是太酷了
You're all heart, Callahan.
你說的真輕鬆，卡拉漢
Am I gonna have to have him leaning over my shoulder?
難道我要把他捧上天嗎？
You work with Briggs on this, Callahan.
卡拉漢，你要跟布立基一起跟進這個案子
But if you ever lean out of line, so help me, I'll flop you lower than whale shit.
如果你又想得寸進尺 我一定會讓你好看的
Speaking of whale shit, what have you turned up, Briggs?
說到這 你為什麼會來找我？布立基
Nobody in my department is sitting on their ass.
我的手下都在忙
See this thing, Callahan? The chief.
仔細聽好了，卡拉漢
He calls me on this all the time. Even in the can.
局長在盯著我這個案子 連我上廁所他都要打電話來追問
I haven't been out of my shoes in 48 hours...
我已經四十八小時沒有合眼了
...and still we have no witnesses, not one.
可是我們到目前為止還找不到目擊者 一個也沒有
In these cases, there's always an officer right on top of the crime.
按常理推斷，像這種案子總是會被一些警員撞見
But nobody's ever seen a thing.
但這次卻毫無線索
- Who was the officer on this one? - A patrolman, Sweet.
那麼這次的事件是誰發現的？ 是一個叫史威特的巡警
Wasn't it, Briggs?
對吧，布立基？
Sweet seems like a good man.
史威特是個好人
I'll get on the ballistic reports first thing in the morning.
我明天一早就會去作彈道比對
We ran all the slugs through ballistics. We'll never see those guns.
我們已經做過彈道比對了
It was too professional, you're wasting your time.
兇手很專業，你這是在浪費時間
Well, it takes me time, Briggs.
好吧，讓我花點時間，布立基
A man has to know his limitations.
人總該知道自己的能力所在
Warm enough?
夠暖和嗎？ 嗯
You're my first cop.
你是第一個跟我上床的員警
Guess that'll be two firsts tonight, won't it?
看來今晚是我們倆的第一次 對吧
What do the others look like?
有其他的發現嗎？
The gun was a. 357 Magnum.
作案用的槍是三五七型的連發手槍
The other bullets are all too deformed to do us any good.
其他的子彈都變形了 根本看不出什麼端倪
Hollow points, fired point-blank, you know. We were lucky to get these two.
沒有特徵，沒有火藥的痕跡 還好能找到這兩個
I found them in the pimp's car.
我是在那個皮條客的車塈鋮鴘
.357 Magnum?
三五七型的連發手槍？
Maybe it's a cop. Maybe it's Harry.
也許是員警幹的，也許是哈媟F的
Nobody hates hoodlums as much as he does.
沒有人像他那樣討厭混混
Whoever it is, he enjoys it.
不管是誰幹的，那傢伙都樂在其中
It's possible the man was dead with the first shot.
這傢伙可能在挨第一槍時就死了
The others were thrown in just for good measure.
接下來的幾槍只是在拿他練靶子
- He unloaded a whole magazine into him. - One big mothering hole, huh?
兇手把一個彈匣堛漱l彈都射完了 在他身上打了一個大洞，對嗎？
Well, everybody has to pay something.
每個人都要付出代價的
He would have to be standing right here, this close...
他應該就站在那堙A那麼靠近
...point-blank range.
....把槍拿出來
The driver's license and the $100 bill were out.
駕駛執照和百元鈔票都掉了出來
Almost like he was showing it to a traffic cop.
像是他要賄賂交警
Yeah.
是的
From what we have, it figures somebody to be impersonating a police officer.
根據我們所知道的，有人在假冒員警
On the cars, at least. It's been done before.
至少他在冒用警車 以前發生過此類事件
This close, it would have to be somebody he would never recognize.
就這麼近，對方一定是他不認識的人
Or never suspect.
或者是不會懷疑他的人
Lou Guzman, ex-meat lugger with a first-grade education.
魯古茲曼，受過高等教育的老牌黑道分子
He started working for the old boss of bosses as a hitter.
一開始，他為黑幫老大當殺手
He controls narcotics state-wide, and now dabbles in prostitution...
現在控制毒品市場 也涉足色情業
...has big friends everywhere. I want Casale and DiGiorgio on him.
到處都有有背景的朋友 我要卡塞和蒂喬治歐盯著他
Next. Thank you.
下一個，謝謝
This one is for your special talents, Callahan.
這是你的專長，卡拉漢
Frank Palancio.
法蘭克帕萊西歐
Two hundred and twelve pounds.
體重二百一十二磅
Complains about his health now.
現在被健康問題所困擾
Suffers from ulcers, migraine headaches. Dangerously violent.
患了胃潰瘍、偏頭疼 有嚴重的暴力傾向
At one point, he was Ricca's principle assassin.
他曾經是雷卡的頭號殺手
If you mix it with him, he won't back off.
由你來對付他，他是沒有機會回手的
He's all yours, Callahan.
他絕對是你的囊中之物，卡拉漢
That's very nice, lieutenant, but I don't think Palancio-
非常好，副局長 但是我並不認為帕萊西歐....
I want you on him, Callahan.
我要你盯死他，卡拉漢
I'd bust Palancio for stepping on a crack on the sidewalk if I could...
聽著，副局長，如果可以的話 我會把帕萊西歐塞進人行道的水溝縫
...but this isn't his style. Not the cars anyway, it's too direct.
但是這不是他的做派 他不會用警車，那太招搖了
Callahan, you just keep your nose pressed against Palancio's ass...
卡拉漢，你只管盯死帕萊西歐
...until I get a warrant from the DA's office to bring him in.
等我申請到拘捕證時就把他抓起來
And I want the first conviction on this animal.
我要讓這個傢伙俯首認罪
Conviction? He's liable to be your next victim.
認罪？ 他很可能是你的下一個受害者
What are you asking for, lieutenant?
你要我怎麼做呢？副局長？
I'm not asking you to follow him, inspector. For the last goddamn time, I'm telling you.
我沒有要你跟著他，警官 但是我最後一次告訴你
Next.
下一個
Nick Royale, Palancio's number-one hitter.
尼科羅耶，帕萊西歐的頭號殺手
He's had good training.
他受過精良的訓練
What's happening?
發生什麼事了？
Nothing, just a lot of peeping and checking, checking and peeping.
沒有什麼，只是例行檢查而已
I knew an old boy once who used to keep pigs under his bed.
我認識一個會把豬放在床上的孩子
Pigs? The eating kind?
豬？可以吃的嗎？
The eating kind. Is all you ever think of your stomach?
可以吃的。你只會想到吃的？
That's very interesting, but I think we better get going.
該死的，我想我們該走了
Yeah.
對
- They're splitting up. Which one, Harry? - We'll stay with these two.
他們分開了，哪一個？哈 我們盯這兩台車
Across the bridge, it's out of our jurisdiction.
聽著，過了橋，就不是我們的管轄區了
Yeah.
是的
Well?
現在呢？
Stick with the money.
繼續盯著
Pull over and stop.
停車
What are you trying to do? He doesn't even know we're cops.
聽著，你想幹嗎？ 他甚至不知道我們是員警
He may panic, and besides, we don't belong over here anyway.
他可能會抓狂的，而且這堣ㄛO我們的管區
I hope he does panic.
我希望他抓狂
Then I'll get him for 23 other murders.
那樣我就能讓他為那二十三件案子付出代價
And if he doesn't...
如果他沒發狂
...then I may be right about something that's been nagging at me.
我心堛熒Q法或許是正確的
I sure hope I'm not.
我希望我錯了
What?
什麼？
I don't wanna be winning bets for anybody.
聽好了，我不想讓別人打賭贏錢
Go a little faster, I'm on their side.
快一點，我這邊比較靠近他們
- Roll down your window. - What? Are you out of your mind?
把窗戶搖下來 什麼？你沒毛病吧？
- I've never been wrong yet, have I? - I don't know why I'm doing this.
快點，我從來都不會失誤，對不對？ 我不知道我為什麼要這麼做
- Say, excuse me. Could you help us out? - What do you want?
不好意思，你能幫幫我們嗎？ 什麼事？
Maybe you could help us, we seem to be lost.
或許你能幫幫我們，我們迷路了
We were looking for the entrance to San Quentin. You know where that is?
我們在找聖昆丁的交流車道 你知道在哪里嗎？
It's back there. Don't you see too good?
你開過了，你的眼珠有問題嗎？
Yeah, I see fine. I just wanted to know whether you knew where San Quentin was.
不，我眼睛很好，我只是想知道 你們知不知道聖昆丁在哪里
And you do, don't you, asshole?
你們不知道，是不是，混蛋
Get you yet, you son of a bitch.
我猜中了吧，這些婊子養的
You always gotta do things your way, don't you?
你老是這麼為所欲為嗎？
No wonder Briggs stays on your tail.
難怪布立基會一直盯著你
You do things someone else's way and you take your life in your own hands.
如果用別人的方法來做事 那你是自己在浪費生命
That son of a bitch Guzman.
該死的古茲曼
He hasn't gone out for almost 24 hours now.
他幾乎整整一天沒出來了
Hey, one of our guys took a spill.
嘿，我們的人出事了
It's Charlie McCoy. Seems to be okay.
是查堻薯狴魽I他好像沒事
Let me take a look.
我來看看
Yeah, he's okay.
他是沒事
There he is.
他出現了
So all you've got to do is sit around all day, Guzman?
你要一整天坐著不動嗎？古茲曼
This coke is out of sight.
這種貨爽歪了
Oh, Guzman is the man, baby.
哦，古茲曼的貨是最好的，寶貝
Oh, you bitch. Don't spill it.
哦，婊子，小心別撒了
That stuff's worth $900 an ounce.
那玩意兒一盎司九百塊
You better not spill it.
你最好別撒了
Don't get so uptight.
別那麼緊張嘛
Nobody says "don't" to me. You understand? Nobody.
沒人敢跟我說“不要”，懂嗎？沒人
I never touch the stuff.
我從來不碰那玩意兒
You wanna put that over there now?
你要把他放到那邊去嗎？
Take over for me, will you, Ed?
你來替替我好嗎？艾德
Damn, I wish something would happen.
天哪，真希望能發生什麼事
Take it easy.
放輕鬆
That's what stakeouts are all about. Waiting.
監視就是這麼回事兒 你必須耐心等待
Frank!
弗蘭克！
- Just what the hell is going on? - Somebody killed a cop.
到底發生什麼事情了？ 有人殺了員警
Folks, there's been a little trouble here. Everyone stand back.
拜託，這是有情況 請大家退後
Please, ma'am, move back.
女士們，先生們，請退後
There's been some trouble.
發生什麼事了？
What happened?
出事了
Everything seems to be all right, folks.
一切都會沒事的
What's going on?
怎麼回事？
Move it, people.
請退後
Please, sir, stand back.
我們是員警，請退後
Yes, sir.
是，長官
No, sir. We won't let anything out to the press.
不，長官，我們會封鎖消息的
Yes, sir.
是，長官
You endangered an entire investigation by trying to push something.
你的急躁使得整個調查行動陷入危機
Not to mention your own lives.
更不用提你自己的小命
You blew the whole Palancio stakeout.
你破壞了監視帕萊西歐的行動計畫
Instead of keeping him under surveillance as I told you to...
而沒有依據我的話去好好監視他們
...you had to harass him. What do you have to say about that?
你就非得去騷擾他們不可嗎？ 現在你還有什麼可說的？
What do I tell Avery? What?
我該怎麼跟艾弗婺挭嚏H怎麼解釋？
You tell him it's not Palancio. You tell him it's a traffic cop.
你告訴他，不是帕萊西歐幹的 你告訴他，是一個交通警察幹的
- A cop? - That's right.
一個員警？
A traffic cop. Are you out of your mind?
交通警察？你在說夢話吧？
Do you expect me to believe that a traffic cop...
你要我相信是一個交通警察
...is killing off all the top criminals in the city? Who?
殺了這個城市的頭號壞蛋嗎？ 那麼你告訴我，是誰？
It's Charlie McCoy.
是查堻薯狴
He's ready for the rubber gun squad. He even tried to kill himself.
他即將被調到搶案組的巡邏分隊 他甚至還想要自殺
Charlie McCoy.
查堻薯狴
...Guzman was hit today.
哈堨j茲曼今天被殺了
A cop was killed. It was Charlie McCoy.
有一個員警也被殺了，他就是查堻薯狴
- McCoy? - Yes, Charlie McCoy.
麥考伊？ 是的，查堻薯狴
The only reason I don't bust you into the bag this minute...
我之所以沒有立刻要你趕到現場
...is I know the two of you were close friends.
是因為我知道你跟他是好朋友
I was just about to call his wife. Or you can, if you want to.
我正準備要通知他妻子 那麼，你來通知她吧
I know he had kids.
我知道他有孩子
Yeah.
是的
- Who reported it? - Davis.
是誰報的案？ 大衛斯
Davis?
大衛斯？
What happened to the DiGiorgio stakeout team?
迪橋治歐的監視小組呢？
It was an accidental coincidence. Davis happened to be going by, it happens.
那是個意外的巧合 大衛斯在事發時剛好經過
McCoy was already dead when he got there.
他到場時麥考伊已經死了
- Any witnesses? - None.
有證人嗎？
- I'll make that call. - Go ahead.
我去打電話 去吧
Harry, if it means anything coming from me, I'm sorry about Charlie.
哈堙A如果你要問我的感受 我為查媟P到遺憾
But it's Palancio, believe me.
但絕對是帕萊西歐幹的，相信我
I'll have a warrant in 48 hours. You can pick him up.
我四十八小時之內能夠拿到拘捕令 你便可以去抓他
He's all yours.
他是你的了
Well, thank you for coming, Harry.
謝謝你趕來，哈
You sure you have to leave?
你確定非要離開嗎？
I won't have any place to go for a sit-down dinner anymore.
我沒有可以免費吃晚餐的地方了
I never really did like it here very much.
我從來都不喜歡這個地方
I always liked the change of seasons.
我喜歡四季分明的氣候
I'm gonna take him home. It's time.
我要帶他回家，是時候了
It's time he went home.
是他該回家的時候了
Come on, kids, let's get in the car.
過來，孩子們，上車了
It was nice of that young man to help us with the children.
那個年輕人真是好心腸 還來幫我照顧孩子
Goodbye, Harry. We'll all miss you.
再見，哈堙A我們會想念你的
Bye, doll.
再見，寶貝
Take them to the passenger terminal, please.
請把他們帶到候機區
It was nice of you to come out. You didn't have to do that.
你能趕過來真的是太好了 其實你不必那麼做的
If I'd have been there sooner, he might still be alive.
如果我能早一點趕到 他或許不會死
He didn't deserve to get it that way.
他不該落得如此下場
If there's anything I can do...
真的希望我能幫忙
I feel responsible somehow.
我覺得我對這件事有責任
The next shooter is Callahan. Davis on deck.
下一位選手是 卡拉漢 大衛斯請做好準備
You sure shot the pants off of everybody with that score, Harry.
你的分數真的把大家都比下去了，哈
I've never seen you smoother.
我從來沒見過你打的這麼好過
By the way, I personally want to tell you...
還有，我要告訴你
...how sorry I am about what happened to Charlie.
我對查堛漲熒P到很難過
What I can't figure out, Frank, is how that kid Davis got in there first.
我有一點就是想不通，弗蘭克 為什麼大衛斯會先趕到現場
You guys were right across the street.
你們就在對面街口啊
I don't have a goddamned idea, Harry. The kid came out of nowhere.
我也不知道啊，哈 孩子們總是莫名其妙的冒出來
We were in that garage before you could spit.
以前不用很久我就可以趕到現場
Maybe I'm slowing down in my old age or something, I don't know.
或許因為我的年紀大了 所以動作慢了，我不知道
I wanna be the first to congratulate you on what I think will be the winning score.
卡拉漢警官，我要第一個恭喜你 你應該得到冠軍
You shaded me by seven points.
你贏了我七分
The only person now who has a chance is Davis.
現在唯一有機會贏你的是大衛斯
Shoot them up.
把他幹掉！
I think the kid beat you, Harry.
我想那孩子把你打敗了，哈
It happens.
總會發生這種事情的
Harry, he edged you by four points.
哈堙A他贏了你四分
That evens it up on the overall champion.
你們兩個要參加最後的總決賽
You have your choice in the shoot-off.
你可以選擇比賽項目
Bull's eye or combat?
打靶還是實戰演練？
Combat.
實戰演練
Out!
完畢！
Five, 46 seconds. Score, perfect.
五分四十六秒，得分，滿分
Good luck, sir.
祝你好運，長官
A good guy! That last one was a good guy.
是好人！
Thirty-six seconds. But I'm sorry, Harry, you hit a good guy.
五分三十六秒 對不起，哈堙A你打到一個好人了
You had a bad break. I really don't deserve it.
你的運氣不好 我不配拿冠軍
Well, you won, didn't you?
你贏了，不是嗎？
- Yes, sir, but- - That's all that matters.
是的，長官，但是- 那才是重點
You mind if I try that one?
你介意我試試你的槍嗎？
Chester, how about six?
查斯特，幫我放六個人靶好嗎？
Not bad. I seem to have lost the last one.
不賴 我最後一個好像沒打到
You get used to it.
你會習慣的
I can see how you would, at that.
是的，我知道，你為什麼會射那麼准了
You said five minutes and I've been waiting for half an hour.
你說五分鐘 結果我等了半小時
Don't you ever get hungry?
你不餓嗎？
- It just didn't seem like a half-hour. - Yeah, well, it has been.
我覺得不像過了半個小時 是的，過了半個小時了
I went over to my butcher's yesterday and picked up some veal.
聽著，昨天我到我弟弟那堮酗F一些小牛肉
Pops is really an artist, man. I could watch that man cut meat all day long.
我的父親是個藝術家，我看著他切了一整天的牛肉
Why don't you come home with me and...
你為什麼不到我家來吃飯呢？
My wife's a good cook. Have a little dinner with us.
我老婆燒菜很在行的 讓我們吃頓便飯
No, thanks. I just saw something that killed my appetite.
不，謝謝了，我剛剛看到的東西 讓我完全沒有食欲了
We'll catch those animals with their pants down. I was going to call you at home.
你們這次能把他們逼得連褲子都穿不上 我會給你家打電話
We got our search warrants and multiple charges.
我們拿到了拘捕令 和多項罪名的起訴狀
We're gonna make a city-wide raid tomorrow morning.
明天早上，整個城市會為了我們而歡呼
Palancio is yours. Just don't take him out head-first, Harry.
帕萊西歐是你的了 別急著要他的腦袋，哈
I think you'll find what I want to show you in ballistics very interesting.
我想你會發現我給你看的彈道痕跡很有意思
You'll find more leads than you can shake a stick at tomorrow morning.
你明天即將找到的線索會多到不計其數
- Good morning, Harry. Sir. - Walter.
早上好，哈堙A長官 華特
Do you mind excusing us for a few minutes?
你能讓我和他單獨呆一會嗎？
Sure.
當然可以
There's only two.
只有兩顆子彈
- I wonder what happened to the others. - Federal boys have them.
我不知道其他的子彈怎麼了 調查局的人拿走了
Well?
所以？
Take a look.
你來看
Close, real close.
非常接近
But there's still a lot of lines that don't match up.
但是有些還是不吻合
All this proves is that these two bullets...
這只能證明這兩顆子彈來自
...came from barrels with a similar twist and width of rifling.
彎度和寬度相似的手槍
You don't think it would stand up as evidence?
你不覺得這是證據嗎？
But I'll have a full comparison report made, no problem.
但我會作出完整的比對報告 這一點問題都沒有
You're probably right. Besides, it isn't necessary yet.
或許你說得對 而且還不需要
What do you mean, "yet"?
你說“還不需要”是什麼意思？
Where'd you get that slug?
那顆子彈你是從哪里弄來的？
- I'd just as soon not say for the time being. - Don't play games on this.
時機成熟我才會說 別耍我，哈
Whose side are you on anyway?
你到底是哪一邊的？
It's just a wild shot and I'm probably wrong.
聽著，我只是在胡亂猜想，或許我錯了
I'd like to handle it my own way.
我希望自己來處理
By the way, I'd like to have Davis and Sweet as my back-up squad tomorrow.
還有，明天我要大衛斯跟史威特來做我的援手
You drum up somebody in the department who can shoot as well and I'll use them.
如果局媮晹魚眭犖j法跟他們一樣好的話 我就請他們來支援我
Goddamn it, there isn't supposed to be any shooting.
該死的 不應該發生槍戰的
Besides, they don't have the experience yet for a job like this.
而且他們的經驗還不足以使他們擔此大任
How the hell's a man supposed to get experience if nobody gives him a chance?
如果不給他們機會 他們怎麼會有經驗呢？
And Davis is the new pistol champion.
還有，大衛斯可是新任的射擊冠軍
Suppose they panic and start shooting?
你覺得他們會不自覺地開槍嗎？
Nothing wrong with shooting, as long as the right people get shot.
開槍沒什麼不對的 只要打對了人，就行了
- Let him know who you are and keep cool. - Okay.
讓他知道你是誰，保持冷靜 好的
I want you to keep an eye on Davis and Sweet.
我要你看著大衛斯和史威特
What for?
為什麼？
Just do it, will you?
照我的話去做就好了
All right.
好的
- You all set? - All set.
你們都準備好了嗎？ 好了
We'll take off in three cars.
我們分別乘坐三部車出發
Davis and Sweet will make the arrest. Early will cover.
大衛斯和史威特負責逮捕他們 厄利負責掩護
I'll be on the back at the pier in case anybody makes a break for it.
我會在後面的碼頭 以防有人想開溜
If there'll be trouble, that's where it'll start.
如果出事，我想那媕雩茯O弱點
We're holding the other squads back until you've made your arrest.
在你們進行逮捕的時候 其他小組會支援你們
- Right? - Right.
好嗎？ 好的
I'd never walk up to a door with Harry, too many people don't like him.
我從來沒有和哈埵b一起混過 大多數人都不喜歡他
Thanks. I needed that.
謝謝，這正是我需要的
- You boys ready? - Yes, sir.
你們都準備好了？ 是的，長官
- Thank you for requesting us. - Sir, we won't let you down.
謝謝你讓我們參加 長官，我們不會讓你失望的
Well, I'm depending on that.
好，那就全靠你們了
Yeah?
喂？
Who is this?
是誰啊？
What was that, Nickie?
怎麼了？尼奇
Somebody said we'll be hit in two minutes. They'll be dressed like cops.
有人說我們在兩分鐘之內會被開槍掃射 對方會偽裝成員警的樣子
Did it sound like anybody you know?
那個聲音聽起來耳熟嗎？
No, I couldn't tell.
不，我沒有聽過
Ed, Chuck...
艾德，查克
...get over to the windows.
到窗戶那邊去
I got the water side.
我負責碼頭那邊
I'll take the street side.
我負責街道這邊
If they are cops, this could be a set-up.
如果他們是員警，這應該是個陷阱
After the holes they put in Ricca you want me to wait and see?
他們把雷卡給做掉了 你要我傻乎乎的坐在這媯扒隉H
If they're cops, they'll have papers.
如果是員警，他們就會帶著證件 你會知道他們是不是員警
Car coming, Frank.
有車靠近，弗蘭克
There's a big guy out there.
外面有個塊頭很大的傢伙
- He got a uniform on? - No.
他有穿制服嗎？ 沒有
He ain't no cop. Cops always come in the front door.
員警會走前門的
Another car.
又來了一部車
Why didn't they come in squad cars if they're cops?
如果他們是員警 他們幹嗎不開警車來？
That big guy's working himself around by those containers.
那個大塊頭躲在桶後面
He's got a gun out.
他把槍拿出來了
Two uniforms in it.
車埵釣潃茯翵謇A的
That ain't no cop's gun, Frank.
那不是警用槍支，弗蘭克
There's a cop in uniform coming up to the door.
有個穿制服的來了
We ain't open. Come back tomorrow.
我們不會開門，明天再來吧
Police officers, we'd like to ask you some questions.
我們是員警，我們想問你幾個問題
I'm just a watchman. Nobody's here.
我只是警衛，沒人在家
We're looking for Mr. Frank Palancio.
我們是來找弗蘭克帕萊西歐先生的
Would you open the door? We have a warrant for his arrest.
請你開門好嗎？ 我們有拘捕令
I said nobody's here, goddamn it!
我說過了沒人在家，該死的
We have warrants for a search of the premises.
我們帶了搜查令來了 請打開門
Serve them!
給他們好看
They got Sweet! Send some help, quick!
快點請求支援！
Cease firing.
快停火
Throw your weapons out and come out with your hands behind your heads.
把你們的武器丟出來 雙手高舉在頭上
- Bullshit! - Fuck you!
廢話！ 去你的！
You sure you don't want a local for this? Takes about seven stitches.
你真的不用止痛藥嗎？哈 你一共縫了七針
No, thanks.
不用，謝謝
Okay, it's your ass.
好吧，隨便你
My head, cut's on my head.
我的天，他們竟然害我破相了
Why does everybody suddenly become a comedian in here?
為什麼這堛漕C個人突然成了小丑？
Does he have to stay in here?
他必須要留在這媔隉H
No, I could stop and let the man's brains run out all over his shoes.
不，我可以停下來 讓他的腦漿濺的到處都是
Rogers, I don't need to have a doctor display that kind of attitude.
羅傑，我不喜歡作為一個醫生是那種態度
A police officer is dead.
一位員警殉職了
Sorry.
抱歉
I got those warrants for a search of the premises, Callahan...
我開的是搜查令，卡拉漢 不是要你來當法官
...not for you to become judge, jury and executioner.
不是要你當陪審團或是行刑手的
It was supposed to be a simple arrest.
那應該是一項簡單的逮捕行動
Arresting a killer like Palancio isn't always simple.
逮捕帕拉西歐這樣的殺手，決不那麼簡單
People are guilty until proven- I mean...
除非有證據，不然沒人是有罪的
Goddamn it, you know what I mean.
該死的，你明白我的意思的
The city's on the edge of the worst violence in its history...
這個城市攪入了一場有史以來 最大的犯罪暴力中了
...and you have to start full-scale military operations.
而你，展開了大規模的軍事整肅行動
I didn't start shooting at anyone who didn't start shooting at me first.
除非人家對我開槍 不然我是不會開槍的
Each time you pull out that gun, my paperwork backs up for three months.
只要你每次一拔槍 我就得寫上三個月的報告
The chief and I have already conferred on this matter.
局長已經和我談過了，卡拉漢
A full investigation is warranted here.
他批准進行大規模的調查
What about a dead cop?
那個殉職的警員呢？
- I warned you against taking them. - Sweet was killed with the first shot.
我警告過你別帶他們去的
Besides, they were tipped off. They knew we were coming, Briggs.
有人已經洩漏風聲給他們 他們知道我們要去，布立基
How? Don't hand me that crap.
怎麼會？別跟我胡說八道的
They knew we were coming. After 200 arrests, I know the difference.
我告訴你他們知道我們要去 我逮捕過無數的壞蛋，這點我看得出來
If I have my way, Callahan, you won't make another arrest as long as you live.
如果我能做主，卡拉漢 在你有生之年是無法再逮捕任何人的
Is that all, lieutenant?
你說完了嗎？副局長
No, that's not all.
不，還沒有完
I want that slug you showed me.
我要那顆你給我看過的子彈
I ran that through ballistics, it was nothing. The rifling was totally different.
我比對過彈道了，根本沒什麼 是不同的槍射出來的
It's still state's evidence. I want it anyway.
它還是州政府的證據 立刻給我交出來
Eat it.
拿去吃吧
Look, Harry, if it means anything, I think you got the wrong end of the stick.
聽著，哈堙A如果這真的代表了什麼 我想你找錯人了
- You do? - Yeah.
你真的那麼想？ 是
What did they find when they got in there?
他們進去時發現了什麼？
Nothing. Palancio was as clean as he could possibly be.
沒什麼。帕萊西歐還是一樣毫無嫌疑
They knew we were coming, Harry.
他們知道我們會去，哈
Why do you figure they opened up on us?
你覺得他們為什麼要對我們開槍？
They must've thought it was a set-up like the others.
他們一定覺得這次行動 就像是其他人中的陷阱
- It was. - No.
沒錯 不會吧
It was a set-up, Early.
這是個陷阱，厄利
What I'm gonna lay on you seems so far-fetched, I can't even believe it myself.
我知道我說的話有點匪夷所思 連我自己都不相信
I gave up being surprised working with you anyway.
自從跟你搭檔以來 什麼事都無法讓我感到驚訝
Would you be surprised if I told you...
如果我告訴你
...a bunch of rookie cops were the ones who were doing all the killing?
是一群菜鳥員警殺了所有的大壞蛋
See this?
你看
I gave Briggs a phony for the time being.
我給布立基的子彈是假的
This is a bullet I took out of the target range.
這是我在靶場
It came from Davis' gun.
從大衛斯的槍堮野X來的
It matches up with the one taken out of Charlie McCoy's body.
它跟從查堻薯狴鴩迨W 取下來的子彈彈道相符
Davis? That's insane.
大衛斯？這太瘋狂了
Maybe so, but somebody tipped-off Palancio that we were coming.
或許是吧，但有人告訴帕萊西歐 我們要去找他
Wanting me killed or Palancio or hopefully both.
他希望我或是帕萊西歐被殺 或是我們兩個都死
Yeah, but Sweet died today.
對，但是今天史威特死了
Sweet was sacrificed.
史威特犧牲了
What's more important, if I'm right, I'll be sacrificed.
更重要的是如果我猜對了 我會犧牲的
They've gotta figure I told you, which means you'll be sacrificed.
他們知道我會告訴你 所以你也會犧牲
Yeah.
對
If anything happens to me, I want you to give that to Lt. Briggs.
如果我死了 我要你把這件事告訴布立基
Okay. What happens if they get us both?
好吧
Then they win.
那麼他們就贏了
It's not hard to understand how this could happen, the way things are.
對，這很難瞭解 為什麼會變成今天這個局面
As incredible as it seems, there may be a sub-organization within the police force.
不可思議的事或許警局 有一股私自運作的力量
Sort of a death squad like they had in Brazil some years back.
像是幾年前巴西警局的醜聞一樣
Damn.
該死
Some nights I wake up, wonder where the hell the world's going to.
有時我半夜醒來 心想這世界到底是怎麼了
I want you to take care of yourself, you understand?
我要你好好照顧自己 你明白嗎？
- Hi.
嗨！
Jesus, what happened to your face?
天啊，你的臉怎麼了？
Nothing, just a few stitches.
沒事，只是縫了幾針
I was going to the market, how about if I bring back a few beers?
我要去買東西 要我買些啤酒回來嗎？
Good, I could use a beer right about now.
好，我現在需要喝點啤酒
I've got your key, so I'll get your mail too.
我有你的鑰匙 所以我會幫你拿信
All right, baby.
好的，寶貝
Keep it warm.
把床弄暖和了
Do you have any idea how hard it is to prosecute a cop?
你知道要起訴員警有多困難嗎？
You heroes have killed a dozen people this week.
你們這些英雄 這個星期殺了十二個人
What are you gonna do next week?
下個星期你們要做什麼？
Kill a dozen more.
再殺十二個人
Is that what you guys are all about, being heroes?
當英雄就是你們走的路嗎？
All our heroes are dead.
我們的英雄都死了
We are the first generation...
我們是學會戰鬥的
...that's learned to fight.
第一代精英
We're simply ridding society of killers that would be caught...
我們想把那些應該被法院判定入獄
...and sentenced anyway if our courts worked properly.
或是被判死刑的壞蛋除掉
We began with the criminals that the people know...
我們從眾人皆知的惡棍下手
...so that our actions would be understood.
那樣大家就會瞭解我們的想法
It's not just a question of whether or not to use violence.
問題不在於使用不使用暴力
There simply is no other way, inspector.
而是沒有別的辦法了，警官
You of all people...
你們應該瞭解的
...should understand that.
你不是加入我們
Either you're for us or you're against us.
就是與我們為敵
I'm afraid you've misjudged me.
恐怕你們看錯我了
- Hi, Sunny. - Hi, Sue.
嗨，桑妮 嗨，蘇
No, no!
不，不！
Harry, what are you doing?
哈堙A你在幹什麼？
Hey, what's going on down here?
發生什麼事了？
I'm taking the mailbox apart, what does it look like?
我要把這個信箱拆了 不然你以為是怎麼回事？
- You people live here, don't you? - Yeah.
你住在這堙A對吧？ 對
What are you doing to the mailbox? Did you lose you key?
你到底要對這信箱怎麼樣？ 你的鑰匙丟了嗎？
Why don't you mind your own goddamn business?
你為什麼不管好你的閒事？
That's my mailbox too. Don't you get smart with me.
那也是我的信箱 別想耍我
Tampering with the mail is a federal offense.
破壞郵件觸犯聯邦法律
I'm calling the police.
我要去報警了
I am the police.
我就是員警
What?
什麼？
The cop that lives upstairs?
你就是住在樓上的員警？
What's that?
那是什麼？
Plastic explosive.
塑膠炸彈
A bomb?
炸彈？
That's right.
沒錯
If you'd bothered me any more, we'd all be stuck to the ceiling.
如果你再煩我 我們全都要被炸上天
- Do you want to hold it? - No. I don't want to get involved.
拿去，你要拿一下嗎？ 不不不，我不想管這件事了
Go to your apartment and stay there. Don't open for anybody.
你進屋子堣d萬別出來 誰來都別開門
Homicide, Lt. Briggs, Inspector Callahan calling.
幫我接兇殺組布立基副局長 我是卡拉漢警官
Callahan, where are you?
卡拉漢，你在哪里？
Look, Briggs, I just found a bomb in my mailbox.
聽著，布立基 我剛剛在我的信箱媯o現炸彈
I want you to get a man over to Early's house right away.
我要你立刻派人去厄利家
- What? - I've got a bomb right here.
什麼？
Now get a man over to Early's, you hear me?
立刻派人去厄利家，聽到了嗎？
Right.
好
Stay right where you are. I'll be down there myself.
你呆著別離開 我會趕過去
Don't move.
別離開
Yeah?
誰？
Come on in.
進來吧
I don't like looking down one of those.
我不喜歡發生這種事情
Where's the bomb?
炸彈在哪里？
Right on the dresser.
在右邊的抽屜
All right. Let's get out of here.
好吧，我們快走吧
Avery will want to see this.
艾弗堣@定知道這件事情的
You mind driving? I want to take a closer look at this thing.
你開車好嗎？ 我想仔細看看這玩藝兒
This thing could be activated by your mailbox key.
炸彈可以用你的信箱鑰匙觸發
Or by a timer.
或是計時器
Turn right, here.
這堨k轉
Get on the freeway.
上高速公路
The freeway?
高速公路？
You got a new route to city hall, lieutenant?
你發現市政廳的新路了嗎？ 副局長
Your gun's out of its holster, Briggs. First time?
布立基，你拔搶了，第一次嗎？
You know you're not going to city hall.
你知道你到不了市政廳的，卡拉漢
The only way you're going anywhere is in a rubber bag.
你只能被裝在屍袋娷鰶}
Let me have your gun.
把你的槍給我
Now the shells.
還有子彈
Three. You always carry three.
三個，我知道你帶三個彈匣
Throw them out the window.
把它們扔出窗外
How do you figure on pulling this off, Briggs?
你怎麼會想出這種事情來？布立基
I run the investigation. With your record, I can make anything stick.
我主導調查研究，從你的報告， 我可以想到任何細節
What I can't understand is, why you of all people?
我不瞭解的是為什麼會是你？
A hundred years ago in this city, people did the same thing.
一百年前人們在這個城市也是這麼做的
History justified the vigilantes, we're no different.
歷史讓義警合法化，我們都是一樣的
Anyone who threatens the security of the people will be executed.
只要是危害到社會安全的人都該死
- Evil for evil, Harry. Retribution. - That's just fine.
以牙還牙，哈堙A這就是報應
But how does murder fit in?
你說得對，但為什麼要謀殺他們？
When police start becoming their own executioners...
當員警自己都成了行刑手
...where's it gonna end, Briggs?
結果會變成怎樣呢？布立基
Pretty soon, you'll start executing people for jaywalking.
很快的，你會殺掉擅自穿越馬路的人
And executing people for traffic violations.
然後是違反交通規則的人
Then you end up executing your neighbor because his dog pisses on your lawn.
最後你因為鄰居的狗 在你的草坪撒尿而殺了他
There isn't one man we've killed that didn't deserve what was coming to him.
我們殺的人沒有一個是不該死的人
Yes, there is. Charlie McCoy.
不，有些不是，查堻薯狴
- What would you have done? - I'd have upheld the law.
那你會怎麼做？
What the hell do you know about the law?
你對法律又懂什麼狗屁？
You're a great cop, Harry.
你是個好員警，哈
You had a chance to join the team, but you'd rather stick to the system.
你有機會加入我們 卻選擇活在體制內
Briggs, I hate the goddamn system. But until someone comes along...
布立基，我憎恨這該死的制度 但除非能有人將它變得合理
...with some changes that make sense, I'll stick with it.
不然，我還是要遵守它
You're about to become extinct.
你就要死翹翹了
Get off at the next exit.
下一個交流通道下去
Red?
瑞德？
Briggs was right. You guys don't have enough experience.
布立基說得對 你們經驗還不夠
Just hold it right there, Callahan.
不要動，卡拉漢
No tricks.
別耍花招
Your organization's through, Briggs.
你的組織已經毀滅了，布立基
There's a lot more where they came from, believe me.
相信我 我在警校媮棬鄑鋮鴔韟h的人
Move out of the way. Move it!
你快給我滾開，快滾！
Uphold the law.
維護法律
You just killed three police officers, Harry.
你剛剛殺了三名警員，哈
And the only reason I'm not gonna kill you...
我不殺你
...is because I'm gonna prosecute you with your own system.
是因為我要用你自己的制度來懲罰你
It'll be my word against yours.
我會出庭作證
And who's gonna believe you?
然而誰會相信你的話呢？
You're a killer, Harry. A maniac.
你是個殺手，哈堙A一個瘋子！
A man's got to know his limitations.
人應該知道自己的能力所在。